Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And we're bringing you another great elementary lesson for all those elementary learners.
我们为所有初级学习者带来了另一节精彩的初级课程。
In today's lesson, we've got some excellent language that will help you to describe someone's
在今天的课程中，我们有一些很棒的语言，可以帮助你描述某人的
appearance.
外貌。
It's something that everyone has learned before in school, describing people.
这是每个人以前在学校都学过的内容——描述人物。
So we're going to review that and give you some better phrases.
所以我们将复习一下，并给你一些更好的短语。
Some real English phrases.
一些真正的英语短语。
Real English phrases.
地道英语短语。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time, and then we'll come back and talk about
那么我们先听一遍对话，然后再回来讨论
it.
它。
I heard you were on a date last night.
我听说你昨晚去约会了。
So how did it go?
怎么样？
I want all the juicy details.
我要听所有劲爆的细节。
Um, well, actually, we had a fantastic time last night.
嗯，实际上，我们昨晚玩得很开心。
He was amazing.
他太棒了。
Okay, now you really have to fill me in.
好了，现在你真得跟我好好说说。
What's he like?
他长什么样？
He's really good looking.
他非常帅。
He's quite tall, around 6'1".
他挺高的，大概一米八五。
He's in his early 30s, and he's got the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
他三十出头，有一双最漂亮的深棕色眼睛。
He sounds hot.
听起来很性感。
What does he do for a living?
他是做什么工作的？
You know what?
你知道吗？
This is the best part.
这是最精彩的部分。
David is a junior investment banker at Fortune Bank.
大卫是财富银行的初级投资银行家。
So he's got a great career path ahead of him.
所以他前途一片光明。
Hold on a sec.
等一下。
His name is David?
他叫大卫？
Yeah.
是的。
That's my brother!
那是我哥哥！
All right, so interesting dialogue.
好了，很有意思的对话。
Small world.
世界真小。
It is a small world.
世界真小啊。
I don't know how I would feel about dating my friend's brother.
我不知道如果和我朋友的哥哥约会会是什么感觉。
Really?
真的吗？
No, I wouldn't feel good about it.
不，我会觉得不太好。
Why?
为什么？
Well, because if you break up with the brother, then like, that means you'll have to end the
嗯，因为如果你和哥哥分手，那就意味着你得结束
friendship with your best friend.
和你最好朋友的友谊。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Dangerous.
危险。
Girls are more complicated with that.
女生在这方面更复杂。
We guys, we're not that complicated.
我们男生，没那么复杂。
Well, you know what?
嗯，你知道吗？
Let's look at the language before this gets too far.
在事情变得太深入之前，我们先看看语言吧。
All right.
好了。
Let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
我们来看看语言要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
On Language Takeaway today, we're bringing you three words.
今天的语言要点，我们带来三个单词。
The first one is heard.
第一个是 heard。
Heard.
Heard。
So you guys know this word.
你们都知道这个词。
It's a substance of hear, right?
它是 hear 的过去分词，对吧？
Right.
对。
But the way it's used is quite interesting.
但它的用法相当有趣。
Let's listen to a couple of examples of how it's used.
我们来听几个例子，看看它是怎么用的。
Example one.
例子一。
I heard you're dating a new guy.
我听说你在和一个新的人约会。
Example two.
例子二。
Julie told me she heard that you're pregnant.
朱莉告诉我她听说你怀孕了。
Example three.
例子三。
What you got fired?
什么？你被开除了？
I heard that you quit.
我听说你辞职了。
So when you say for example, oh, I heard you were pregnant.
所以当你说，比如，哦，我听说你怀孕了。
Whoa.
哇。
This is like telling someone that you found some information about them, but you're not
这就像告诉别人你发现了一些关于他们的信息，但你
sure if it's true or if it's false.
不确定这是真的还是假的。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Our next word, fill me in.
下一个词，fill me in。
Fill me in.
Fill me in。
So when you tell someone to fill you in.
所以当你让别人给你补上信息时。
You're saying tell me about it.
你是在说告诉我这件事。
Tell me the details.
告诉我细节。
I could say, I'm sorry I was late for the meeting.
我可以说，对不起我开会迟到了。
Can you fill me in on what happened?
你能告诉我发生了什么吗？
Exactly.
没错。
Or I could say, I missed the first five minutes of the movie.
或者我可以说，我错过了电影的前五分钟。
Fill me in.
给我补上。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Great word.
好词。
And our last phrase today, career path.
我们今天的最后一个短语，职业道路。
Career path.
职业道路。
So what's a career path?
那么什么是职业道路？
I guess this is the plan for your job over several like 10 or 20 years.
我想这是对你未来十年或二十年的工作规划。
Right.
对。
So the jobs and things you do during your career.
所以就是你职业生涯中从事的工作和事情。
Yeah.
是的。
That's your career path.
那是你的职业道路。
So in this case, David has a really good career path because he's going to be a really rich
所以在这个例子中，大卫有一条非常好的职业道路，因为他会成为一个非常富有
and powerful investment banker.
且有权势的投资银行家。
Yes.
是的。
So career path.
所以是职业道路。
Very good.
非常好。
So now let's listen to our dialogue again and pay special attention to the language
现在让我们再听一遍对话，特别注意描述大卫的语言，
used to describe David because when we come back, we're going to talk about this.
因为我们回来后会讨论这个。
Irene, I heard you were on a date last night.
艾琳，我听说你昨晚约会了。
So how did it go?
怎么样？
I want all the juicy details.
我想知道所有劲爆的细节。
Um, well, actually we had a fantastic time last night.
嗯，其实我们昨晚玩得很开心。
He was amazing.
他太棒了。
Okay.
好吧。
Now you really have to fill me in.
现在你真得跟我好好说说。
What's he like?
他长什么样？
He's really good looking.
他非常帅。
He's quite tall, around 6'1".
他挺高的，大概一米八五。
He's in his early 30s and he's got the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
他三十出头，有一双最漂亮的深棕色眼睛。
He sounds hot.
听起来很性感。
What does he do for a living?
他是做什么工作的？
You know what, this is the best part.
你知道吗，这是最精彩的部分。
David is a junior investment banker at Fortune Bank.
大卫是财富银行的一名初级投资银行家。
So he's got a great career path ahead of him.
所以他前途一片光明。
Hold on a sec.
等一下。
His name is David?
他叫大卫？
Yeah.
是啊。
That's my brother.
那是我哥哥。
So we found some really great words and phrases used to describe someone.
我们找到了一些用来描述某人的很棒的单词和短语。
Exactly.
没错。
There's a lot of language in here talking about the way someone looks.
这里有很多关于描述某人外表的语言。
So let's listen again as Irene describes David.
那我们再听一遍艾琳描述大卫。
He's really good looking.
他真的很帅。
He's quite tall, around 6'1".
他很高，大概一米八五。
He's in his early 30s and he's got the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
他三十出头，有一双最漂亮的深棕色眼睛。
He's really good looking.
他真的很帅。
He's quite tall, around 6'1".
他很高，大概一米八五。
He's in his early 30s and he's got the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
他三十出头，有一双最漂亮的深棕色眼睛。
Okay.
好的。
So let's break this down.
我们来分解一下。
The first thing she says is, he's really good looking.
她说的第一句话是，他真的很帅。
Good looking.
好看。
So good looking is the equivalent of handsome.
所以“good looking”相当于“handsome”。
Or pretty.
或者“pretty”。
Pretty.
漂亮。
Yeah.
是的。
Good looking.
好看。
But I think good looking sounds a lot more natural than handsome.
但我认为“good looking”听起来比“handsome”自然得多。
Yeah.
是啊。
You wouldn't really use handsome.
你不会真的用handsome。
Like I would never say that.
我绝不会那么说。
Even though it's correct.
尽管它是正确的。
It's just good looking sounds much more natural.
只是good looking听起来自然得多。
I guess for me, whenever someone says handsome, it sounds like an older person.
对我来说，每当有人说handsome，听起来就像是个年纪大的人。
Yeah.
是啊。
It sounds old fashioned.
听起来很老派。
Like my grandma would say, oh he's a handsome young man.
就像我奶奶会说，哦，他是个英俊的年轻人。
Yeah.
是啊。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So she says, he's quite tall.
所以她说，他挺高的。
Quite tall.
挺高的。
So we know quite means very.
所以我们知道 quite 意思是“很”。
Yeah.
嗯。
And tall, we know.
而 tall 我们知道。
Right.
对。
So you can describe a person in different ways.
所以你可以用不同的方式描述一个人。
Yeah.
是的。
He's quite tall.
他挺高的。
He's kind of tall.
他有点高。
He's sort of tall.
他算比较高。
He's a bit short.
他有点矮。
He's not that short.
他没那么矮。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So these are great words we can use to describe someone's height.
所以这些是我们可以用来描述某人身高的好词。
Okay.
好的。
Then, she talked about his exact height.
然后，她谈到了他的确切身高。
Yes.
是的。
Right.
对。
She said he was 6'1".
她说他身高6英尺1英寸。
6'1".
6英尺1英寸。
Around 6'1".
大约6英尺1英寸。
Yeah.
嗯。
This is interesting because in the United States and Canada, you give a person's height
这很有趣，因为在美国和加拿大，人们用英尺和英寸来表示身高。
using feet and inches.
使用英尺和英寸。
That's right.
没错。
Right.
对。
So we don't talk about meters and centimeters.
所以我们不说米和厘米。
Right.
对。
So 6'1 would be 6 feet 1 inch.
所以6英尺1英寸就是6英尺1英寸。
Exactly.
正是。
But in other countries, you would talk about centimeters or meters.
但在其他国家，你会说厘米或米。
So 6'1 is like, 6'1 is about 180.
所以6英尺1英寸大概是180。
Yeah.
嗯。
About that.
差不多。
So this is an interesting difference between...
所以这是一个有趣的差异，介于……
Like English-speaking countries and European countries.
比如英语国家和欧洲国家之间。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So the next time you give your height to someone, make sure you do it in feet more
所以下次你告诉别人你的身高时，确保你用英尺来
or less.
大致表示。
It sounds a lot more natural.
这样听起来自然得多。
And actually, if you say to somebody in Canada, for example, I'm 175 centimeters, they wouldn't
实际上，如果你对加拿大人说，比如，我身高175厘米，他们
know really how tall that was.
真的不知道那有多高。
How tall that is.
那有多高。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Now, the next part is really, really useful.
现在，下一部分真的非常有用。
She said he's in his early 30s.
她说他三十出头。
In his early 30s.
三十出头。
His early 30s.
他三十出头。
Early 30s.
三十出头。
So this is a way of describing someone's age without actually giving the exact number.
这是一种描述某人年龄而不给出确切数字的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
So for example, early 30s.
比如，三十出头。
So like 32, 33.
大概32、33。
Mid 30s.
35岁左右。
Like 34, 35, 36.
比如34、35、36。
Oh, 36.
哦，36。
Yeah.
对。
And then late 30s would be?
那快40岁是？
38, 39.
38、39。
And you could do the same thing for...
同样的方法也适用于……
Like 40s.
比如40多岁。
40s, 50s, 60s.
40多岁、50多岁、60多岁。
20s.
二十多岁。
Yeah.
对。
20s.
二十多岁。
You wouldn't do this before your 20s.
你在二十岁之前不会这么做。
I don't think it's really common to talk about your teens.
我觉得谈论十几岁并不常见。
Right.
没错。
You wouldn't say like his mid-teens or early teens.
你不会说“他十几岁中期”或“十几岁早期”这样的话。
Yeah.
对。
Sounds a bit weird.
听起来有点奇怪。
Okay.
好的。
Great language used to describe people.
用来描述人的语言很棒。
But one more word.
但还有一个词。
Right.
对。
He's hot.
他很性感。
Or he sounds hot.
或者他听起来很性感。
Yeah.
是的。
He's hot.
他很性感。
Yeah.
是的。
So this is another sort of informal way of describing someone who's really good-looking.
所以这是另一种非正式的说法，用来形容某人非常好看。
Good-looking.
好看。
Really sexy.
非常性感。
Right.
对。
He's hot.
他很火辣。
Yeah.
是的。
But it is informal.
但这是非正式的说法。
It is really informal.
这非常不正式。
Maybe even a little bit offensive.
甚至可能有点冒犯。
You wouldn't go up to a girl and say, wow, you're hot.
你不会走到一个女孩面前说，哇，你真性感。
No.
不会。
It's a little bit too impolite.
这有点太不礼貌了。
Right.
对。
You would say, wow, you're really pretty or you're gorgeous.
你会说，哇，你真漂亮或者你真美。
But you wouldn't say, wow, you're hot.
但你不能说，哇，你真性感。
No.
不会。
You would never say that to somebody.
你永远不会对别人那样说。
Right.
对。
That's something you would comment with your friends.
那是你会和朋友评论的事情。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So we've looked at some really good language for describing people.
所以我们看了一些描述人的很好的语言。
Now we could listen to our dialogue a third time and I'm sure you will understand everything.
现在我们可以第三次听对话，我相信你会理解所有内容。
I heard you were on a date last night.
我听说你昨晚去约会了。
So how did it go?
怎么样？
I want all the juicy details.
我要听所有劲爆的细节。
Um, well, actually we had a fantastic time last night.
嗯，实际上我们昨晚玩得很开心。
He was amazing.
他太棒了。
Okay.
好的。
Now you really have to fill me in.
现在你真得跟我好好说说。
What's he like?
他长什么样？
He's really good looking.
他非常帅。
He's quite tall, around 6'1".
他挺高的，大概一米八五。
He's in his early 30s and he's got the most beautiful dark brown eyes.
他三十出头，有一双最漂亮的深棕色眼睛。
He sounds hot.
听起来很性感。
What does he do for a living?
他是做什么工作的？
You know what?
你知道吗？
This is the best part.
这是最精彩的部分。
David is a junior investment banker at Fortune Bank.
大卫是财富银行的一名初级投资银行家。
So he's got a great career path ahead of him.
所以他前途无量。
Hold on a sec.
等一下。
His name is David?
他叫大卫？
Yeah.
是啊。
That's my brother.
那是我哥哥。
Okay, so we looked at really useful language for describing people and we want you to describe
好了，我们学习了一些描述人的实用表达，希望你能用来描述
your girlfriend, boyfriend.
你的女朋友、男朋友。
Or even yourself.
甚至你自己。
What do you look like?
你长什么样？
How tall are you?
你多高？
How old are you?
你多大了？
Yeah.
嗯。
And try and use the language from today's lesson.
试着用今天课上学到的语言。
Right.
好的。
So come to EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments on our website.
所以来EnglishPod.com，在我们的网站上留下你的问题和评论。
And your descriptions.
还有你的描述。
And your description.
And we'll definitely be there to answer any doubts as well.
而且我们一定会到场解答任何疑问。
Yes.
是的。
Well guys, thanks for listening today.
好了，各位，感谢今天的收听。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
再见。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。